This is a sweet story.
这是一个甜蜜蜜的故事
Romantic.
浪漫
Then?
然后呢
Then...
然后
There was nothing romantic.
就跟浪漫没什么关系了
How poor Xiaoyu was!
小鱼好可怜啊
Right, Xiaoyu was poor.
是 小鱼真的太可怜了
And she just told me
而且这件事
about this thing.
她就告诉了我一个人
And she emphasized thousands of times
而且千叮咛万嘱咐
that I can't tell anyone else.
让我谁也不要告诉
Or she will kill me.
不然就弄死我
So don't tell anyone else
你们千万不要
please.
告诉别人啊
Why don't you eat?
你怎么不吃啊
What are you thinking?
想什么心事呢
What's wrong with you?
你这个人怎么回事
Why do you come back suddenly?
你为什么突然回来了
Well, you can come back.
你回来就回来
But why do you treat me with dinner?
你干嘛请我吃饭啊
Well, you can treat me with dinner.
请我吃饭就请我吃饭
But why do you treat me alone?
为什么单独请我吃饭呀
Do you want to be my boyfriend?
你是不是想跟我处对象
Then you should ask me directly
那你问我呀
if I have a boyfriend.
有没有男朋友
What if I have a boyfriend?
万一我有男朋友呢
Say something.
你倒是说话呀
It's bad that
我直接说我有男朋友
I say I have a boyfriend.
这事不好吧
It seems that
好像显得我
I think too much.
戏特多的似的
Why do you come back suddenly?
你怎么突然回来了
I heard from classmates that
我听同学说
you went to university abroad.
你去国外读大学了
It's spring break.
正好放春假
I come back this time
这次回来
to be the leader of my friend's debate team.
给我朋友辩论队当领队
I remember
我记得
you liked to debate
你高中的时候
when you were in high school.
也喜欢打辩论吧
Right.
嗯
I'm debating now.
我现在也在打
So he comes back for coaching the debate team.
原来是当辩论队教练呐
In fact,
其实
I come back this time
我这次回来
for one person.
是为了一个人
What's wrong?
怎么了
Well.
那个
Then?
然后呢
Nothing.
没什么
I just come back.
这不刚回来吗
Let's catch up
这顿饭
over this meal.
我们就叙叙旧吧
Eat.
快吃吧
What are you two doing?
你俩干嘛呢
Get in and see for yourself.
自己进去看吧
Write a love song for you.
写一首情歌给你
Can't sing unfinished.
唱不出未完待续
Take all the...
把所有的
Stop crying.
你再嚎
I told you
我跟你说
that if you cry any more,
把宿管大爷嚎上来
You'll be happy
把咱们那些限量款杂志
when he takes away
全都收走了
all our limited edition magazines.
你就开心了
Are you crazy?
你抽风啊
Are you serious?
你玩真的
Hey.
哎
He was dumped.
被甩了
She is, after all, a goddess
人家毕竟是女神
and encounters many temptations.
遇到的诱惑多
This thing was like this.
这个事 好像是这样
Jingwen
静雯
Our...
我们
Our track and field team has extra training today.
我们田径队今天加训
I have tried my best
我已经很努力地
to get here.
往这儿赶了
But I was still a full
但是 我还是
three minutes late.
足足迟到了三分钟
It's okay. I don't mind.
没事 我又不介意
It's not okay!
不行
I'm a man.
我一个男人
I made you wait for me here.
我让你在这儿等我
I'm such a failure.
我太失败了我
It's okay.
没事
Let's have dinner first.
我们要不先去吃饭吧
Let's go.
走
What's wrong with you?
你怎么了
Could you wait me for a minute?
能等我一分钟吗
I just ran too fast
我刚才跑太快
and got a leg cramp.
腿抽筋了
Are you okay?
你没事吧
I'm okay.
没事
Do you want to sit for a while?
要不我扶你坐会儿
No!
不用
I can walk.
我能走
Wait. Wait.
你等一下等一下
Listen to me.
你听我说
We can have a rest there.
我们先去那边歇着
We can have dinner
然后等你缓过来了
when you feel better, okay?
我们再去吃饭好不好
We have plenty of time anyway.
反正我们时间还久啊
What's wrong with you?
你怎么了
Nothing. Nothing.
没 没
I, I just feel
我 我就是觉得
so
太
so happy.
太幸福了
No girl has ever been
从来没有
so nice to me.
女孩对我这么好
Alright. Let's go now.
好了 我们先过去
I'm sorry.
对不起
Take care.
慢点 慢点
This one.
要一个这个
Then a plate of green asparagus.
然后再来一份青笋
A plate of artemisia stalks.
再来一份蒿子秆
And two plates quail eggs.
再外加两份鹌鹑蛋
Okay.
好的
Anything else?
请问还有什么需要的吗
You like bland food.
你喜欢吃清淡的
Don't put pepper in
我们所有的菜
any of our dishes.
一丁点辣都不要
And put less salt.
然后再少放点盐
Okay.
好的
By the way, I want
那个 再加两份
two plates of beef and lamb hind legs.
牛肉跟羊后腿肉
You like these.
你不是喜欢吃吗
Make them more tingly and spicier, thanks.
还要加麻加辣 谢谢
No. No.
不 不用了
We don't take the dishes she ordered.
她说那些都不用了
We just have what I ordered.
就要我说的那些就行
Okay. Please wait for a minute.
好的 请二位稍等
The dishes you ordered
你说的那些菜
have a strong flavor.
味道太重了
Even if I eat them,
就算是我吃
it'll affect your
也会影响你
consumption.
用膳的
Jingwen, please don't be angry.
静雯 你别生气了
I'm not angry.
没有啊 我没生气
Really?
真的
Really.
真没生气
Oh my! Don't
哎呀你真的
be angry.
你别生气了
From dinner to now,
从吃饭到现在
you should have calm down.
你也应该消气了吧
Even if you're still angry,
就算你不消气
you should tell me
你也应该告诉我是
what I said
我说错了哪句话
or did wrong.
或者是做错了哪件事
You want me to tell you the reason or you find it by yourself?
是我说还是你自己想
You tell me.
你说
I got it. I got it.
我知道了 我知道了
It is because I
是不是因为我
was late just now.
刚才迟到了
Or
或者说刚才
the meal just now was not to your liking.
那顿饭不合你的口味
Alright. Alright.
好了好了
Anyway, it's my fault.
反正我做错了
I did everything wrong.
什么都是我不对
Jingwen. I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
静雯 对不起 对不起
Stop!
你别再说了
Mengyuan, I want to have a talk with you.
梦圆 我想跟你谈谈
Okay.
嗯
As a result,
结果
she...
她
How can this happen?
怎么会呢
Does she happen to be in a mood
你说你是不是赶上人家
these days?
心情不好的那几天了
No.
不
It can't be true.
不能够
It must be
这肯定又是那个
the problem
不要和女生讲道理
that never reason with girls.
那个问题
I don't think so.
我不觉得啊
And I think there's
而且我还觉得
nothing wrong with Mengyuan.
梦圆做得没毛病啊
Right?
对吧
I also don't think
我也觉得
I did anything wrong.
我做得没什么毛病
Don't worry.
你放心
Jingwen is not
静雯不是那种
a capricious girl.
耍小脾气的姑娘
Maybe she is in a mood.
没准就是她心情不好
And you don't know the situation.
你还不了解情况
This makes her angry.
就生气了
You should wait.
你再等等
Wait.
再等等
She'll calm down soon.
过一会儿就消气了
But it has been three hours.
可是已经三个小时
She hasn't responded to any of my messages.
她没有回我任何消息
According to my experience,
以我身经百战的
I think
经验来看
after a good sleep,
今天晚上睡一觉
tomorrow morning,
明天一睡醒
hey,
哎
she maybe let it go
没准想开了
and won't be angry anymore.
没准消气了
You can come to her at this time.
这个时候你找她
Thing will be done.
那肯定就好了
Hey bro.
那位大哥
You can really bear it.
你也太能忍了吧
I have just practiced how to close my five senses recently.
最近刚修炼的封闭五官
Do you want to learn?
要不要传授给你啊
I tell you
我跟你们说
being in love
谈恋爱这个事
is a new beginning relationship.
就是一段新开始的关系
And boys usually can't realize it.
男生呢 往往意识不到
As the ancients used to say
古人有云
cultivate the bitterness of love
修炼爱情的心酸
and let go of past desires.
放掉过去的渴望
That's the lyrics!
那不歌词嘛那是
Yeah.
啊
I come to give you...
我前去给你
Hello.
喂
Hello. Come out to buy milk tea.
喂 出来买奶茶了
Why do you drink milk tea again?
怎么又喝奶茶啊
Aren't you afraid of
你也不怕
becoming too fat to deserve me?
喝胖了配不上我
How dare you?
谁借你的胆子
But I don't have time.
那什么 我现在没时间
Mengyuan is dumped
梦圆不知道为什么
in no reason.
失恋了
I'm comforting him now.
我现在正安慰他呢
Let's make a hypothesis
那假设
that you are dumped
你知道自己是因为
because of
一杯奶茶
a cup of milk tea.
被分手了
Do you
你认为这个假设
like this hypothesis?
怎么样呢
Wait for a minute.
我马上到
Then they broke up?
就分了
Don't you think Mengyuan is poor?
你说梦圆惨不惨吧
I think
我觉得
it is because he is too cowardly.
他可能是因为太   了
He has been like this.
他都练成那样了
You say he is cowardly.
他还
How do you get this conclusion?
他哪儿   了
The thing is like this.
你看 是这样
At first,
一开始呢
it is his manliness
是因为他的男子气概
that attracts Jingwen.
吸引的静雯
But now, he indulges her everywhere.
现在呢 处处迁就她
Jingwen thinks,
静雯就觉得
hey,
哎
he is not the one
不是最初
she liked primarily.
喜欢的那个样子了
He has changed.
变了
Yeah.
嗯
I find your girls' thoughts
我发现你们女生的思想
are really abnormal.
真是变态啊
Is it a bad thing to be nice to her?
对她好还不行啊
If I become
那假如说以后我要成
as naive and straightforward as Mengyuan in the future,
梦圆那样的耿直憨厚
will you not like me anymore?
你是不是也不喜欢我了
No way.
不会的
You are too feminine to change.
你娘们叽叽的怎么会变
But I still can't agree with
但是我还是不认同
your girls' opinions.
你们女生的观点
However,
不过啊
I think my girlfriend
我觉得我女朋友
is more reasonable.
还是比较通情达理
Right.
是的
Gong Chen
宫晨啊
Gong
宫
Chen?
晨
Right.
对
Why... Why didn't you tell me in advance?
你 你怎么不报备啊
I told you
我跟你说了
that I would have dinner with a friend.
我跟一朋友吃饭
But you haven't told me
跟朋友吃饭
the friend is him!
你也没跟我说是他呀
You haven't asked me.
你不是也没问吗
I, I haven't asked?
我 我没问
What else did you do besides having dinner?
除了吃饭还干嘛了
We chatted about the old days.
就聊聊以前的 以前的事
Apart from
除了
chatting,
聊天
did he send you back?
他 他送你回去没
Why should he send me back?
他送我干嘛
We're not on the same route.
我们又不顺路
Are you jealous?
吃醋
No, I'm not.
我没有
I...
我
I care about you.
我在关心你
Well. Well.
哦 哦
So feminine.
娘们叽叽
I have arrived.
我到了
I'll leave.
上去了
You are leaving now?
这就上去了
I haven't finished the milk tea.
奶茶还没喝完呢
You have training tomorrow.
明儿早还得训练呢
Don't you need to go to bed early?
你回去不得早睡啊
Alright,
那这样的话
I have to wait 11 hours
就还得等十一个小时
to see you.
才能见到你了
Don't close the window
那你晚上睡觉的时候
when you sleep at night.
别把窗户关上好不好
What?
干嘛
Don't you afraid the dormitory manager finds you?
你不怕阿姨发现啊
Then
这样
I can come into your dream
我就可以顺着窗户
through the window.
进入到你的梦里了
Don't
以后
say such corny honeyed words anymore.
别说这种土味情话了啊
Don't you think it is disgusting?
腻歪不腻歪
It's not for kids. It's not for kids.
少儿不宜 少儿不宜啊
Where are the kids?
哪有少儿啊
Me.
我呀
You can go now.
跪安吧
You told him?
你跟他说了
I told him half of the things.
说一半
Flirt is no use.
撩都撩不动
That's great.
真好
What did you talk about just now?
你们两个刚刚说什么了
Nothing.
没
He just said his school was on spring break.
他就说他学校放春假
He came back to be a coach
回来给一个辩论队
of a debate team.
当教练来着
He said he came back
他说他这次回来
for one person.
是为了一个人回来
But I don't know who he came back for.
但不知道是谁
That must be you.
那肯定是你啊
I told you
我就说了
he knew you
当年你喜欢他的事
liked him in those years.
他知道
So he must think
所以说他现在
you are good now.
一定是念着你的好
And he came back for you.
现在回来找你
Nonsense.
少来了
Have you told him
那你跟他
that you have boyfriend?
说你有男朋友的事了吗
I tell you
我跟你讲
I was just about to tell him
我真的刚要跟他说
when Nan Bei called out of the blue.
南北突然打电话过来
I was scared.
吓死了
Do you still
你不会对他
like him?
还余情未了吧
No way! Sister.
怎么可能 大姐
I'm really single-minded, okay?
我超专一好不好
I saw his face
我现在看到他那张脸
with no feelings anymore.
真的是一点感觉都没有
Alright.
好吧
I think you and Nan Bei are matched anyway.
反正我可是站你跟南北
Stop gossiping about me, okay?
你少八卦我了好不好
What about you?
你自己的事怎么样
The specialized segmentation
细分专业
will collect forms tomorrow night.
明天晚上交表格了
Alas.
哎
Don't mention it.
别提了
I told my mom yesterday
我昨天跟我妈说
that I want to have a try.
我想试试
Then?
嗯
Then my mom said
结果我妈说
I'm overconfident
我这叫盲目自信
and lack of self-cognition.
缺乏自我认知
To be honest,
说 说实话
after hearing these words,
我听多这些话
I doubt
我都在怀疑自己
if I can do this.
是不是不是这块料
Well.
嗯
I support you,
我支持你
baby.
宝宝啊
Hey, bro.
大哥
Can't you stop
大周末的
for the weekend?
能不能消停会儿啊
I was just dreaming about Jingwen.
我刚才梦到静雯了
I dreamed that she told me
我梦到她跟我说
the breakup was a joke.
分手是闹着玩的
I was so happy.
我好开心呐
I rushed up to send her a message.
我赶紧起来给她发消息
However,
结果
however, I found
结果我发现
that she has ghosted me.
她给我拉黑了我
I want to ghost you, too.
我都要把你拉黑了
Oh my god.
我的天爷
If you are so sad,
你既然这么难过
you should get her back.
你就挽回呀
Right, you should go to Jingwen.
对呀 你找静雯去啊
Leave us alone!
放过我们吧
The cheekier you are,
感情这种事情
the longer you will last
谁脸皮最厚
in a relationship.
谁就能挺得越久
Right.
没错
By the way,
而且啊
the more you pay attention to the small details,
越是小细节
the more you can make her feel
越能让人家
that you care about her.
觉得你在乎她
You can do like this.
你可以这样
Flower.
鲜花
Yeah, right, flower.
对 没错 就是鲜花
No girl
没有一个女孩
can resist
可以抵挡住
the fragrance of flowers.
鲜花的芬芳
Jingwen
静雯
I have something for you.
我有东西想送给你
What?
什么东西
What's wrong with you?
你怎么了
I'm allergic.
我过敏
Why do you buy flowers if you're allergic?
你过敏买什么花啊
Are you stupid?
你是不是傻
I think it's...
我觉得浪
romantic.
漫
I'm so touched by your behavior.
你这种行为我很感动
But please don't
但请你以后
do this in the future.
不要用这种方式了
Jing...
静
Jingwen
静雯
That's it?
这就完事了
Then I think game is over.
那我是觉得 没戏了
No.
不
On the contrary,
相反
he has opportunities.
是有戏
And he really has opportunities.
还是很有戏的那种
Think about it.
你仔细想想
Don't forget
你可不要忘了
that Jingwen took the flower.
静雯是把花拿走了的
And when she took the flower,
而且拿走的时候
she said
还撂了句话
"in the future".
以后
This proof you have a future.
这证明就还有以后啊
Really?
真的
Oh my!
哎呀
Yes.
没错
Let's move on to the next step.
咱们开始下一步
You can pester her.
你还可以死缠烂打
Make her feel your love,
让她感受到你的爱
your goodness.
你的好
Her heart
她的芳心
will definitely belong to you.
也一定会被你黏住
Jingwen, you can focus on your class.
静雯 你好好上你的课
Just pretend I don't exist.
就当我不存在
It is hard
这件事情要想
for this thing
从这个人的内心
to change
发生改变
in one's heart.
几乎是很难的
As a result,
因此啊
human should
人首先是要
make sure that...
杜绝自我在遇到问题
Shouldn't you
你这个时候
be training with the track team at this time?
不应该在田径队训练吗
I just want to be with you.
我只想跟你黏在一起
Everything else is not important.
其他的都不重要
Each processing method
每一个处理方法
produces a corresponding
都会产生一个相应的
body.
主体
Where to start,
从哪里开始
where to go from there.
就从哪里出发
Make love return to the point of origin.
让爱回到原点
Let love
让爱
set sail again.
再次扬帆起航
When she comes,
一会儿等她来了
you get down on one knee
你就单膝跪地
in this circle.
在这个圈里
Make sure she feels
一定要让她感受到
that you are sincere in your apology.
你道歉的诚意
When she forgives you,
等她原谅你了
you scatter the balloons.
你再把气球这么一撒
It means
这就代表
letting go of the past
放下过去
and looking forward to a better future.
展望美好的未来
Thank you, buddy.
谢谢你 好兄弟
My pleasure.
没事
That's all I can do for you.
兄弟只能帮你到这儿
The rest is up to you.
后边就只能靠你自己
She's coming. She's coming.
来了来了
Ready.
准备
Jingwen
静雯
I have something to tell you.
我有话要跟你说
I know
我知道
I may have done something wrong
我可能做错了什么
or expressed something wrong
或者表达错了什么
that has caused you to misunderstand.
让你产生了误会
I want to tell you
我只想告诉你
that no matter what happens in the future,
无论以后发生什么
I will be by your side
我都会无时无刻地
all the time,
陪在你身边
taking care of you and protecting you.
照顾你 保护你
Jingwen
静雯
please forgive me.
原谅我吧
How romantic!
好浪漫啊
So romantic.
太浪漫了
Oh my!
天啊
Why does she go?
她怎么走了
What does she tell you?
跟你说啥了
Does she forgive you?
原谅你了吗
Jingwen says
静雯跟我说
she breaks up with me.
她跟我说分手
Jingwen
静雯
Leave here.
别看了
She breaks up with me. She breaks up with me.
她说分手 她说分手
Bro, give me that, okay?
大哥 你给我吧 行不行
Please.
求求你了
Play the wrong BGM?
背景音乐放错了
Mengyuan
梦 梦圆
Turn down the music first.
你先把这声音小点
Pull yourself together!
你 你振作起来
You pick yourself up.
你打起精神来
Let's do it again.
我们再来一次
Again what?
再 再来什么呀再来
Your strategy is wrong.
就是你的方案错了
You should follow my plan.
就该按照我的计划来
Have you ever been reliable with your plan?
你那计划靠谱过呀
I'm reliable than yours.
我靠不靠谱
Now game is over.
你现在人彻底凉了吧
I'm reliable or not?
靠不靠谱
I haven't said...
彻不彻底
Listen to me. I haven't said
不是 彻不彻底凉
the game is over.
我还没说过呢
Our plan is just beginning.
我们的计划才刚开始
Bro, stop singing.
大哥 你别唱了
Look at me.
看我吧
Stop. Stop. Stop. Don't touch him.
别别别 你别弄人家了
Does it really calm the mind?
这玩意儿真能安神吗
You'll get the result tonight.
你今天晚上就知道了
What are you talking about?
你们俩在说啥呢
We're talking about whether this tea
我们是在说这个茶
can help us catch up on sleep.
能不能帮助我们补觉
You guys don't know
你们是不知道
that we were kept awake for days and nights
这两天我们被梦圆弄的
by Mengyuan's noise for the past days.
几天几夜没睡着
I've heard from the boys in my class
听我们班男生说了
that your dorm room
说你们寝室就跟
is like a ringing bomb.
炸了铃似的
There's a single song loop every night,
每天晚上都有单曲循环
and someone cries.
还有人哭呢
So scary.
这么瘆人
Bro.
大哥
Give us a favor.
帮帮忙吧
Do something
为咱们宿舍脱离苦海
to help put our dorm out of its misery.
出一份微薄的力量
What can I do?
我怎么帮
Can you, me and Dandan, the three of us
你 我 蛋蛋三个加起来
beat Mengyuan?
打 打得过梦圆吗
Kids
孩子们
The topic of the next debate is out.
下一场的辩题出来了
What is it?
是什么
In a relationship
在恋爱关系中
should we go with the flow
应该顺其自然
or manage it?
还是努力经营
Our holding side is to work hard.
我们的持方是努力经营
Love topic.
爱情题呀
I'm good at this.
我擅长
You have experience.
有经验呗
Mengyuan happens to have experienced it.
梦圆这不刚好那什么嘛
A good example.
我这正好 好好的例子
Really?
是吗
How about sharing
那有什么经验
your experience?
分享一下呗
If you want to end a relationship,
你要嫌自己感情没凉透
you can ask him for advice on his experience.
你就向他讨教经验喽
Nonsense.
不是
Mengyuan is a special case, a special case.
人梦圆是个特例 特例
Generally speaking,
一般情况
anyone who's been begged so hard
像这么努力挽求
would have already agreed, right?
早就已经同意了 是吧
It's not that he doesn't work hard.
他不是不努力经营
He doesn't know
他那是不懂得
how to manage reasonably.
如何合理地经营
It's different from our debate topic.
他跟咱辩题是两回事
I agree.
我同意
Efficient management counts.
有效经营才算数
Ineffective efforts
无效的努力
are counterproductive.
也就适得其反
So it proves
所以说就证明了
love has to be managed with brains
爱情是要用脑子
and heart.
用心经营的
It depends.
那也得分情况吧
The kind of thing that goes with the flow,
你像我和小鱼这种
like me and Xiaoyu,
顺其自然的
is definitely true love, isn't it?
那肯定是真爱是吧
You mean you wouldn't read books anymore
你的意思就是考完试
after the exam, right?
再也不用看书了是吧
Read after exam?
考完试看
It's not the same thing. Don't fool me.
不一样啊 你别坑我
Feelings are mutual in a relationship.
感情里边是相互的
What's the most important thing in a relationship?
里边最重要的是什么
It's trust.
是信任
Second, it's communication.
其次是沟通
Based on this,
在这个基础上
to run a better relationship
为了更好地经营感情
and to avoid some trouble,
为了避免一些麻烦
it is not necessary
就没必要什么事
to let your partner know everything,
都让对方知道
right?
对吧
No.
不是
If you trust each other,
既然是信任
you should say everything.
那就应该什么都说啊
If the other person
那要是一方觉得
doesn't feel the need to say it,
没必要说
it doesn't matter if you say it or not,
说不说无所谓的
you can leave it out.
可以不说呀
You are talking about the debate topic, right?
你们俩是在聊辩题对吧
The problem is bigger now.
那更有问题了
You said trust is foundation just now.
你刚刚说信任是基础
But now,
然后现在
you say if the thing is not important, you won't say.
不重要就不说了
Then it's up to you
那说不说
whether you say it or not.
完全看你心情喽
Not everything
也不是所有
is unnecessary.
都是不必要的呀
If you find out later,
要是以后知道的话
I can explain.
我可以解释啊
You can explain?
你解释
What are you not telling me?
你有什么事瞒着我
Does anyone want to go to the bathroom?
有没有人想上厕所
I.
我
Is it popular for girls
女 女孩都流行
to go to the bathroom together?
结伴上厕所
It must be
可能是一个
an ancient tradition.
古老的传统吧
Come out and see the exhibition at the weekend.
周末有空出来看展吧
Hao
小好姐
What happened to your hand?
你手怎么了
This?
这个
This morning
我今天上午
when I was moving something in the office,
去办公室搬东西的时候
I cut my hand.
划到了
There was only one small box,
本来只是个小箱子
but I haven't expected there were more and more boxes.
但没想到越积越多
It took me several trips
我一个人
to move it all by myself.
搬了好几趟才搬完
If you need to do something like this in the future,
你以后要有这种事情
tell me and Dango.
告诉我跟团子嘛
We both eat so much food
我们两个饭吃那么多
that we can do this kind of heavy work.
可以干这种重活的
Okay.
好
So in the future,
所以以后啊
it's better to settle things early.
还是要早点解决
Otherwise, it will become more and more troublesome.
不然的话越来越麻烦
Let's go.
走吧
Hello senior.
师哥好
Let's have lunch tomorrow.
明天中午一起吃个饭吧
So now
所以现在
we should clear
我们首先要明确的一点
what's
就是
the difference between
在爱情中
going with the flow and managing love
顺其自然和努力经营
in a relationship.
有什么区别
What's the difference?
有什么区别呢
Of course, there is difference.
当然有区别了
The difference is...
区别就是
To manage love hard
努力经营爱情
is to be good to him with all your heart.
就是用心地对他好
Then it's not good for him
那顺其自然
to go with the flow?
就是对他不好喽
That's not the point.
不是这个意思
If your feelings disappear,
感情要是消失了
you don't have to be nice to him.
就不用对他好了呀
You have to continue to be nice to him after the feelings are gone.
消失了还要继续对他好
That's what you call trying to manage, right?
这才叫努力经营是吧
Of course not.
那肯定不是啊
So what's exactly
那所以到底
the difference
努力经营和顺其自然
between going with the flow and managing love?
有什么区别
It's
这个就是
managing it.
努力经营
Managing love
努力经营嘛
is very deliberate.
就很刻意啊
You don't say anything.
你这不跟没说一样吗
The distinction between the two
这两者的区别
does seem a little blurred.
确实有点泾渭分明啊
Hao, you have experience.
小好姐 你有经验
You say something.
你来说吧
It seems that you don't have experience.
感觉跟你没经验似的
I'll bite you.
我咬你
I think
我觉得
in a relationship
在爱情中
going with the flow means
顺其自然应该就是
when your partner annoys you,
当对方惹你生气
you can lose your temper.
有脾气就发出来
You can speak out your opinions directly.
有意见就直接说
The couple can
两个人在一起的话
stay with each other
就完全按照
in the way they want to be.
自己的心意在一起
The opposite of that is managing love.
与之相反的话就是经营
It means
应该就是
when you are angry,
在你生气的时候
you think about
你会考虑一下
whether you should lose your temper or not.
这个脾气到底要不要发
But
但是
you do all this
你所有的一切的目的
to make
都是为了
the relationship better.
让两个人的感情更好
I see.
醍醐灌顶
It's a bit wordy.
就是有点啰唆
You should
你应该再多一些
summarize your expressions.
表述总结一下
It means this?
是这个意思吗
Nan Bei and I
那我跟南北在一块
are just going with the flow.
就属于顺其自然呗
We both don't have that worry.
我俩就没有这个顾虑
Are you sure?
真的
What do you mean?
你怎么个意思
He means
意思就是
he took all the grievances for you.
他帮你把委屈都承担了
Let's call it a day.
那今天先到这儿吧
We all go back
大家都回去
to think about how to express it.
想想该怎么表达
Then look up
然后今天提到的论点
all the arguments mentioned today as well.
也都查查资料
Okay, Hao.
好呀 小好姐
By the way, Xiaoyu,
对了 小鱼
I have something to do later.
我一会儿还有事
You go to dinner with Nan Bei.
你跟南北去吃饭吧
What?
啊
I. We...
我 我们
I've asked
我约了
Dandan and Mengyuan to play games together.
蛋蛋和梦圆一块开黑
I accompany you?
我陪你
No, no thanks.
不 不用了
You play games together.
你们一起开黑吧
It's good to accompany Mengyuan.
你多陪陪梦圆挺好的
I'll be fine on my own.
我自己一个人没事
What?
什么
Mengyuan went to cry under Jingwen's dormitory again?
梦圆又去人楼下哭去了
Tonight
今天晚上
we should prepare a pair of
咱俩都得准备一副
earplugs.
耳塞了
Fine.
就这样吧
Hello?
你好
Hello.
喂
Where are you?
在哪儿呢
Have you started playing games?
开始开黑了吗你们
Why do you ask this?
怎么了
Are you missing me?
想我了
Kind of.
算 是吧
Are you in the dorm?
在寝室呢
If you miss me,
你要是想我
I can have lunch with you.
我可以陪你吃饭
Okay.
行啊
If you can come to me
你要是五秒钟
in five seconds,
你能到我面前
I'll buy you a meal.
我就请你吃饭
Okay.
嗯
Five.
五
Okay for what?
你嗯什么嗯
Four.
四
It seems that
好像你知道
you know where I am.
我在哪儿似的
Two.
二
One.
一
Surprise!
惊喜
The old altar pickled beef noodles.
老坛酸菜牛肉面
It seems good.
这家不错
You track me?
你跟 你跟踪我
I haven't tracked you.
我没跟踪你啊
It's love that guides me.
是爱在指引我方向
Come on.
走吧
This one.
就这家了
What do you want to eat?
你看你想吃什么
Anything is okay.
我吃什么都可以
You order.
你点吧
Waiter.
服务员
Where's the bathroom?
你们这卫生间在哪里啊
Go out and turn left.
出门左转
Okay.
好嘞
I go to the bathroom, Nan Bei.
我去个卫生间啊 南北
Senior.
师哥
Here I am.
到了
This way. This way.
这边这边 这里
Didn't we agree
我们不是说好
to eat at the place next door?
去隔壁那家吃吗
The one next door is not as good as this one.
隔壁那家没有这家好吃
You're still
你还是跟以前一样
as surprising as ever.
出人意料
Order now.
点菜吧
Senior
师兄
Take your time.
菜先不着急点吧
I want to tell you one thing first.
我来是想跟你说一件事
We can talk about it
有什么要说的
during eating.
我们边吃边聊
No.
不是
I tell you first.
我先跟你说吧
When you were abroad,
就是你出国这段时间吧
I...
我
Come on.
快来呀
When you were abroad,
你出国的这段时间
and after I go to university,
我上大学了之后
in fact, I have...
其实我已经
Where are you?
人呢
Are you okay?
要紧吗
The dishes are ready. Hurry up.
菜齐了啊 快点啊
The dishes are getting cold. I'm coming for you.
菜都凉了 我来找你啦
Waiter.
服务员
Where's
你们这边卫生间在
the bathroom?
哪里呀
Go out and turn right.
出门右转
Okay. Thanks.
好的 谢谢
Senior, I go to the bathroom first.
师兄 我先去个卫生间
I'll tell you the thing later.
等下回来跟你说啊
Which bathroom takes you such a long time?
去哪儿上厕所了这么久
Did you come back to school?
你回学校了
I went to the bathroom in school.
我回学校上的
The bathroom here
我去这边的厕所
looks terrible.
看起来不太美好
So I came back to school
于是我就回学校
and go to the bathroom there.
上了个厕所
Eat now.
快吃点菜
Noodles are not ready.
面一会儿才上呢
Okay.
好
Oh my!
啊
I left something in the bathroom.
我有东西落在厕所了
I go to take it.
我去拿一下
I'll come back soon.
等会儿就回来
What is it?
什么东西呀
Something you don't know.
你不知道的东西
Senior
师哥
You're back.
回来了
The dishes are ready. Eat now.
菜都点好 快吃吧
You are so kind.
你太客气了
I really
我真的
want to tell you one thing.
我就想跟你说一句话
3760. Thanks.
三七六零 谢谢
Xiaoyu, what's the matter?
小鱼 你怎么了
My neck is a bit twisted.
脖子有点拧着了
Xiaoyu
小鱼
Hello, Shui. What a coincidence.
你好 水哥 好巧啊
Why do you ignore me?
你为什么不理我
This is my senior. This is Shui.
这是我师哥 这是水哥
This is Shui. This is my senior.
这是水哥 这是我师哥
Hello.
你好
I...
我
I come here for take-away.
来取外卖
Is there anything else?
你还有什么事吗
It's too late. I have to go.
来不及了 我先走了
Hello. 4123 take-away.
老板 四一二三外卖
Shui, why are you here?
水哥 你怎么在这儿
Nan Bei
南北
Why are you here?
你怎么在这儿
I wait for Xiaoyu to have lunch together.
我等小鱼一块吃饭啊
Well.
那
Where's Xiaoyu?
小鱼呢
She went to bathroom to take things.
她去厕所拿东西去了
Nan Bei
南北
I decide to tell you one thing.
我决定告诉你件事情
Xiaoyu, I have told you last time
小鱼 我上次跟你说过
that I came back
这次回来
for one person this time.
我是为了一个人
I want you to help me pursue one person.
我想让你帮我追个人
I have got a boyfriend.
我有男朋友了
Well, congratulations.
那得先恭喜你啊
We can have dinner sometime.
改天一起吃个饭
What's wrong?
怎么了
Nothing.
没事
Well. Senior.
怎么了 师哥
Which girl do you like?
喜欢哪家姑娘
An opponent I met in high school
高中时候
when I went out to debate.
出去打辩论认识的对手
We have been chatting on WeChat since then.
之后一直都有微信聊天
And we have also gone out for dinner together.
也一起约出来吃过饭
I originally planned to make a confession.
本来 我打算表白的
But
但是
I planned to study abroad.
后面要去留学
So there's nothing more.
就没有然后了
So you come back this time
那你这次回来
for making a confession?
是打算告白吗
But
但是
I don't know how to confess.
我不知道应该怎么说
And I don't know her thought.
也不知道她是什么想法
By the way,
对了
you have seen her.
你见过她的
Before I study abroad,
留学前
I took her to the KFC
我带她去过你
where you worked.
打工的肯德基
I remembered.
想起来了
Her name is Weiwei.
她叫薇薇
She is the leader of my debate team.
是我这次辩论队的领队
Then you must
那你可得把握好
take advantage of this opportunity.
这次机会啊
Don't worry, senior.
你放心 师哥
If you need me,
只要我能帮上的
I'll try my best to help you.
我肯定尽力帮你
But when thing is done,
但事成之后
you should treat me a big meal.
你可得请我吃顿大的
Of course.
肯定的
And you can take your boyfriend. That's great.
再叫上你男朋友 正好
Mu Xiaoyu. What are you doing?
牧小鱼 你干嘛呢
This is?
他是
I'm her boyfriend.
我是她男朋友
Yes.
是
Senior
师哥
This is
这就是我刚才
my boyfriend Nan Bei
跟你说的
that I mentioned just now.
我男朋友南北
This is my senior from high school, Gong Chen,
这是我从国外回来的
who has returned from abroad.
高中的学长宫晨
Come on. Let's eat together.
我们坐下来一起吃一点
No, thanks.
不吃了
I have a table of food next door.
我隔壁还一桌子菜呢
How did you get tickets
你怎么会有
to this exhibition?
这次展览的门票
I've heard that tickets are sold out before the year.
我听说年前就卖完了
None of my classmates got it.
我们班同学都没抢到
Well.
哦
My
我
friend gave me.
朋友送的
Take a look, beauty.
美女 你看一下
This is a unique version.
这是独一版
I had a hard time getting it.
我好不容易收的
And it's the only one in the exhibition.
而且全场独一份
How did you get this set of comics?
您怎么会有这套漫画呀
It's out of print.
这都绝版了
And this set of comics is not popular.
而且这个漫画是冷门的
This is a treasure for others
这个在别人那儿是宝贝
but not for me.
在我这儿就一般
When it was published,
当时他漫画出版的时候
no one even bought his comic.
根本没人买
But I liked it at first sight.
但我一眼就看上了
I bought dozens of them.
买了几十本
I've had them in my collection for five or six years.
放了五六年
I am now selling it for fifty times its price.
这不 五十倍价格出手
I don't have that much money.
我没有那么多的钱
I'll buy it when I've saved up enough money.
等我攒够了钱再买吧
Do I scan this QR code?
老板 是扫这里吗
Okay now.
好了
Consider that I borrowed it from you.
就当我借你的
I will return the mortgage to you.
我一定按揭还你
Just pay it back with your puffs,
就用你的泡芙
and biscuits.
和曲奇来还吧
Okay, you can have as much as you want.
好 绝 绝对管够
This exhibition will only be held for a few days.
这个展就几天
There's no other place to buy it
过了这个村
after this exhibition.
就没这个店了
And this comic
而且这个漫画
is really rare.
真的很少了
You are very discerning.
你真的是非常有眼光
I'm a comics student myself.
我自己也是学漫画的
It's great that you draw comics.
画漫画厉害呀
But the hard part
但难的还是找一个
is finding an editor with a discerning eye.
慧眼识英雄的编辑
Otherwise, there is no chance
不然画得再好
for a good painting.
也没有机会
This cartoonist
这个漫画家
wouldn't have had to suffer for so many years
如果早年遇到他的伯乐
if he had met his good judge of talent in his early years.
又何苦熬那么多年呢
Let's go and see something else.
咱们去看看别的吧
Okay.
好
I know
我知道
it seems that
我看起来好像
there's something.
有什么事一样
But I tell you
但我告诉你
there's nothing.
百分之百没有任何事儿
If nothing is going on,
没有任何事
why didn't you tell me?
为什么不告诉我
I'm afraid you'll be angry if I tell you.
告诉你怕你生气
If nothing is going on,
没有任何事
why are you afraid I'll be angry?
你怕我生什么气
I'm afraid you'll think too much of it.
怕你多想
If there's nothing,
没有任何事
what am I thinking about?
我多想什么呀
Shui
水哥
Where's Wangwang?
我旺旺呢
My son.
儿子
You mom runs away with others.
你妈跟人跑
Where's my son?
我儿子呢
He's always been there.
一直在那儿啊
Xiwang
喜旺
What are you doing?
干嘛
It's great that you draw comics.
画漫画厉害呀
But the hard part
但难的还是找一个
is finding an editor with a discerning eye.
慧眼识英雄的编辑
Otherwise, there is no chance
不然画得再好
for a good painting.
也没有机会
This cartoonist
这个漫画家
wouldn't have had to suffer for so many years
如果早年遇到他的伯乐
if he had met his good judge of talent in his early years.
又何苦熬那么多年呢
Hello, dad.
喂 爸爸
My girl. What are you doing?
闺女 在干嘛呢
You may not believe me.
说出来你可能不信
I'm studying.
我在学习呢
You are studying?
在学习呢
You are waiting for dinner
是在等着吃晚饭
or midnight snack?
还是等着吃夜宵啊
No.
不是
I'm
就是还在这儿
filling the professional forms.
填专业的表格呢
Girl
闺女
In fact, as long as you are confident
其实只要你有信心
and sure of yourself,
有把握
dad is all for you.
爸爸都支持你
Although you're a little overconfident,
虽然 你有点过于自信
a little over-optimistic,
有点过于乐观
and a little whimsical,
有点异想天开
I...
可是
Well. Well. Well. I see.
好了好了好了 我知道了
Alright. Eat more for dinner.
行吧 晚饭多吃点
Don't starve yourself.
别到时饿瘦了
And said I mistreat you.
回头说我虐待你
Dad
爸
I decide to
我决定
choose an editor.
选择编辑了
Alright.
好
Girl
闺女
Do you have money for a big dinner this weekend?
周末有钱吃大餐吗
I'll give you some more money.
我再给你打点生活费
Great. I want five hundred yuan.
好 我要五百
Okay.
好
Five hundred yuan.
五百
You're back, dorm chief.
寝室长 你可算回来了
Stop Mengyuan please.
你快管管梦圆吧
The dorm next door
隔壁寝室都要
is going to sue us for disturbance.
告我们扰民了
Well. Another one.
得 又来一个
What's wrong with you?
你又咋的了
I lost my girlfriend and I lost my duck.
折了夫人 又折鸭
Why don't I take you
要不晚上
to sing with me tonight?
哥们领你唱歌去
You'll be better after singing.
嚎出来就好了
What do you think?
怎么样
That's great.
那敢情好
You can also take Mengyuan with you.
你把梦圆也带走
Then I'll have a good dream.
这样我就能睡觉了
Are you still our friend?
你还是不是兄弟啊你
Well. Your story
不是 你那故事
has no ups and downs. It's boring.
没起伏 无聊死了
I ask you,
我问你
you don't really suspect Xiaoyu, do you?
你不会真的怀疑小鱼吧
I don't really suspect her.
我也不是真怀疑她
But
但是
the way she handled the matter
她处理这件事情的态度
was awful.
太恶劣了
She didn't even think about
她根本就没有想到
how much
这件事情对我的伤害
this thing was hurting me.
有多大
If Jingwen hadn't broken up with me,
只要静雯不跟我分手
I would have done anything for her.
要我怎么样都行
Is that Xiaoyu?
小鱼吗
No.
不是
Hello.
喂
What took you so long to call me?
你怎么才给我打电话呀
Forgetting your old love when you have a new one.
有了新欢就忘旧爱
Right?
是不是
Well.
嗯
Okay. Then...
可以啊 那
Then
那过两天
I'll order you a room in a couple of days.
我直接给你开间房呗
Okay. I'll pick you up.
好 那我回头去接你吧
Yeah.
嗯
Oh.
哟
Who is it?
谁呀
My childhood friend.
我发小
He said he was coming to see me in a couple of days.
说过两天要来看看我
I see.
懂
You see what? It's a man.
懂什么呀 男的
If you don't tell Xiaoyu,
你不说
how does she know it's a man,
小鱼怎么知道是男的
right?
啊
I'll do the same thing
以彼之道
that she has done to me.
还施彼身
The power finally ran out.
终于没电了
We are liberated.
解放了